start with a right triangle with legs of
length A and B and a hypotenuse of
length C use the hypotenuse as the
radius of a circle centered at the left
point of the triangle with radius C the
horizontal distance from the right angle
to the circle is then C minus a when we
inscribe a triangle in the top
semicircle like this by the's triangle
theorem this triangle is right angled
one consequence of this fact is that
these two pictured right triangles here
must be similar as their top angles are
compliment because the two triangles are
similar their leg ratios must be equal
that means that C + a / B must equal B /
c - A but this equality means that C + a
* c - A = b^ 2 so that c^2 - A 2 = B ^2
from this we see that c^ 2al A2 + b^2
where A and B are the legs of a right
triangle with hypotenuse C we used a
semicircle to prove the Pythagorean
theorem